<?xml version="1.0"?>
<compendium xmlns:exsl="http://exslt.org/common" version="5" auto_indent="NO">
	<class>
    <name>Cook</name>
    <hd>8</hd>
    <proficiency>Constitution, Charisma, Animal Handling, Arcana, Athletics, Medicine, Nature, Performance, Perception, Sleight of Hand, Survival</proficiency>
    <spellAbility/>
    <numSkills>3</numSkills>
    <armor>light armor, medium armor</armor>
    <weapons>simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</weapons>
    <tools>Cook's Utensils</tools>
    <wealth>4d4x10</wealth>
    <autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="NO">
				<name>Starting Cook</name>
				<text>As a 1st-level Cook, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>• Armor: light armor, medium armor</text>
				<text>• Weapons: simple weapons,  hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</text>
				<text>• Tools: Cook's Tools</text>
				<text>• Skills: Choose three from Animal Handling, Arcana, Athletics, Medicine, Nature, Performance, Perception, Sleight of Hand, and Survival</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>• (a) a longsword or (b) a hand crossbow</text>
				<text>• (a) leather armor or (b) scale mail</text>
				<text>• (a) two daggers or (b) two light hammers</text>
				<text>• (a) an explorer's pack or (b) a scholar's pack</text>
				<text>• Cook's Utensils and a Cook's Bag</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.2</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="NO">
				<name>Cook's Bag</name>
				<text>At first level, you craft a Cook's Bag, a bag that magically preserves not only your morsels (described below), but also the ingredients required to make them.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You must replenish these ingredients at least once every 30 days. When you do so, you can buy 10 gp worth of food from a market, or you can spend 8 hours scavenging food from your surroundings.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>f you lose this bag, you can create a new one by expending 100 gp worth of leather, gems, and other raw materials. Doing so takes 8 hours of work.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.2</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
		<feature>
			<name>Morsels</name>
			<text>Years of cooking have taught you that every meal has that one perfect bite, a morsel where all the ingredients mix together into something truly special. You have learned how to instill this morsel with magical effects dependent on the ingredients of the morsel. Creatures that ingest your morsels are given these effects.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>Choose three morsels of your choice, detailed at the end of the class description. These are the morsels that you can prepare. A creature can only be under the effects of one morsel at a time. If a creature is under the effects of a morsel, and they ingest another morsel, the original effect ends</text>
			<text/>
			<text>You learn how to prepare additional types of morsels as you level as detailed in the Cook Table. Each time you gain a level, you can replace one morsel you know with a different one.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>You can cook a number of morsels equal to your Constitution modifier every short or long rest. You can cook the same type of morsel more than once. All morsels are stored in your Cook’s Bag and expire if taken out for longer than 6 seconds, or the next time you cook morsels.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>You can use your action to feed a morsel to a creature. When you do so, you reach into your Cook’s bag, pull out a morsel, and feed it to a conscious creature you can touch. They ingest it immediately. You must have a free hand to feed a morsel</text>
			<text/>
			<text>Saving Throw: Some of your morsels requirie your target to making a saving throw to resist the effect. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</text>
			<text>	Morsel save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier</text>
			<text/>
			<text>Creatures who do not have mouths or analogous orifices can still be affected by your morsels. Mere contact with your morsels imparts a weakened effect. If a creature cannot ingest your morsel, it has advantage on any saving throws it makes against the morsel's effect.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>Source: Cook Class p.3</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1"> <counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>3 </value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3"> <counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>4 </value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="4"> <counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>5 </value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="5"> <counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>6 </value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6"> <counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>7 </value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7"> <counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>8 </value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="8"> <counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>9 </value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="9"> <counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>10</value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10"><counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>11</value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11"><counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>12</value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="13"><counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>13</value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15"><counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>14</value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
	<autolevel level="17"><counter><name>Morsels Known</name><value>15</value><reset>S</reset></counter></autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Smelling Salts</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you discover a mix of spices that creates such a visceral and powerful assault on the nose as to break a creature from its stupor. You can use a bonus action to choose one creature that you can touch. You wave the spices under the creature's nose, and it can immediately repeat a saving throw against one condition it currently has, ending the condition on a success. The condition can be the Charmed or Frightened condition.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once a creature repeats a saving throw with this feature, it cannot do so again until it finishes a short or long rest.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>At 7th level, the chosen condition can be the Stunned condition.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>At 13th level, the chosen condition can be the Paralyzed condition.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>At 17th level, the chosen creature has advantage on the repeated saving throw.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.3</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with cook's utensils. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
				<text>    At 9th level, you can choose two more of your proficiencies (in skills or with cook's utensils) to gain this benefit.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.3</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
			<feature>
				<name>Cook Archetype</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you emulate in the exercise of your cook abilities: Sous Chef, Mess Sergeant, Hash Slinger, Brewmeister, or Monster Masher, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your archetype choice grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 6th , 10th, 14th, and 18th level.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.3</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Cooking Archetype: Sous Chef</name>
				<text>The archetypal Sous Chef believes that their allies are more than worthy of their cooking. They have proven that their stomachs can make the most of the powers instilled in morsels, and a Sous Chef will use that power to safeguard their health at all costs.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Additionally, when you feed a morsel to a willing creature that you can touch (other than yourself), you can do so as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="5">
			<feature>
				<name>Rotund Reflection</name>
				<text>At 5th level, you gain the ability to repel enemies that attack you. Your stomach is of utmost importance, and you have toned your belly to be tough and somewhat gelatinous. When a Large or smaller creature within 5 feet of you hits you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to cause the creature to make a Dexterity saving throw against your Morsel save DC. On a failed save, their speed becomes 0 until the end of the turn, and they are either pushed 10 ft. away from you or knocked prone (your choice).</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Secret Sauce (Sous Chef)</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you create a signature sauce that you dab onto all of your beneficial morsels. Whenever you feed a morsel to a friendly creature, it regains a number of hit points equal to your Constitution modifier.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="7">
			<feature>
				<name>Order Up</name>
				<text>Beginning at 7th level, when you make morsels during a long rest, you can make a number of additional morsels equal to your Constitution ability modifier, none of which can have prerequisites. </text>
				<text/>
				<text>At 11th level, you can make these additional morsels during a short rest as well as during a long rest.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="9">
			<feature>
				<name>Iron Stomach</name>
				<text>At 9th level, a lifetime of eating any and all sorts of foods has prepared your stomach for anything. You are immune to any ingested poisons and the poisoned condition.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Aromatic Scent (Sous Chef)</name>
				<text>By 10th level, the continuous consumption of culinary delights has infused your body with a thousand revitalizing smells that stir your companions to action. As an action you can expel these smells in one powerful wave. All friendly creatures (including yourself) within 30 feet of you that you can see regain a number of hit points equal to your Cook Level, and they can each immediately use their reaction to make a single weapon attack or cast one cantrip they know that requires an attack roll or saving throw (their choice).</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
				<counter><name>Aromatic Scent</name><value>1</value><reset>L</reset></counter>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Magnificent Meal (Sous Chef)</name>
				<text>Beginning at 14th level, you can prepare a magical feast that strengthens both body and will. You gain the ability to cast the Heroes' Feast spell. When you do so, you replace the material components of the spell with fine foods worth at least 500 gp, which the spell consumes.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once you cast Heroes' Feast in this way, you cannot do so again until you have finished a long rest.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 109</text>
			</feature>
			<counter><name>Magnificent Meal</name><value>1</value><reset>L</reset></counter>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="15">
			<feature>
				<name>Soul of Food</name>
				<text>At 15th level, you have attuned your body's life force to the nourishing energies of the world. You can cast Create Food and Water once with this feature and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you do so, you create 100 gold pieces worth of food that is not bland, but flavorful and enjoyable.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>In addition, if you make morsels, and you have no ingredients left, you conjure the necessary ingredients as part of making the morsels.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
			<counter><name>Soul of Food</name><value>1</value><reset>L</reset></counter>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
				<text>	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Player's Handbook p. 108</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="17">
			<feature>
				<name>Fulfilling Meal</name>
				<text>At 17th level, whenever you feed a morsel to a creature that you have shared a long rest with (including yourself), you can double the duration of the morsel’s effect.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Legendary Morsel</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you gain the ability to make the following morsel when you take a long rest. When you do so, you can make only one. It doesn't expire until your next long rest, and it doesn't count against the total number of morsels you can prepare.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Monkey’s Brains. The well-seasoned brains of the world’s most capable simians. For 10 minutes, if the target fails a saving throw, they can choose to succeed instead. If they choose to do so, this morsel's effect ends.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
    <autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Leftovers</name>
				<text>At 20th level, when you roll initiative and have no morsels left, you conjure one morsel that you know how to prepare inside your Cook's Bag.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Source: Cook Class p.4</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
  </class>
</compendium>